Guide to the Chancellor of the University of Pittsburgh, J. Dennis O'Connor, Administrative Files, 1991-1995 UA.2.10.1991-1995
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Chancellor of the University of Pittsburgh, J. Dennis O'Connor, Administrative Files
1991-1995
ULS Archives & Special Collections
University of Pittsburgh. Chancellor
UA.2.10.1991-1995
70.63 Linear Feet (70 record center boxes, 2 document cases)
This collection is comprised of material relating to J. Dennis O'Connor's tenure as Chancellor of the University of Pittsburgh from 1991-1995. It includes material regarding ongoing developments with the university, the changing relationship with the University of Pittsburgh Medical Center (UPMC), and Chancellor O'Connor's actions in the larger community.
Biography
J. Dennis O'Connor served as the sixteenth chancellor of the University of Pittsburgh from 1991 until his resignation in 1995. During his term he struggled with budget issues and the ramifications of Chancellor Wesley Posvar's controversial retirement plan. He worked to increase diversity at the university, implementing several different affirmative action programs for undergraduate and graduate students. O'Connor also oversaw the construction of Sutherland Hall, an undergraduate dormitory on upper campus, as well as the development of a Master Space Plan for Pitt.
O'Connor came to Pitt from the University of North Carolina (UNC), where he served as vice chancellor of academic affairs and provost, making him the highest-ranking academic official at the school. Prior to his time at UNC, O'Connor also served in several positions at the University of Southern California, including dean of the division of life science and chair of the biology department. He also served as a visiting professor at Monash University in Melbourne, Australia, and University of Nijmegan in Holland. O'Connor earned his B.S. from Loyola University in Chicago, his hometown. He earned a master's degree from DePaul University, and received his Ph.D. from Northwestern University in 1968.
After stepping back from the chancellorship, O'Connor intended to take on a faculty position in the department of biology at Pitt. In December 1995, however, O'Connor left Pitt for the Smithsonian Institute, serving as Provost of that institution. He was also briefly the acting director of the National Museum of Natural History. In 2002 he left the Smithsonian for the University of Maryland, College Park to serve as their head of research and dean of graduate studies. He resigned from that role in 2004.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged with respect to the original order created by the Office of the Chancellor. This includes retaining the structure of their filing system, referred to as the Mail Log Files. Material was kept in the categories decided upon by staff at the time of its creation, with exceptions to those documents shown to be obviously misfiled. The categories for the mail log are as follows:
01. Office of the Chancellor
02. Secretary of the University
03. Office of the Vice Chancellor for Student Affairs
04. Vice Chancellor for Institutional Advancement
05. Department of Athletics
06. Clerk of the Senate
07. Affirmative Action
08. Office of the Provost
09. Senior Vice Chancellor for Health Sciences
10. University of Pittsburgh Medical Center (UPMC)
11. Senior Vice Chancellor for Business & Finance and Treasurer
12. Associations and Organizations
13. Colleges and Universities
Each of these 13 categories has subcategories that follow, with individual number assignments of their own. These are included in the folder titles of the files in the collection. It should be noted that for the first year of Chancellor O'Connor's tenure, the Office of the Chancellor used the same numbering system as Chancellor Posvar's office did; this changes with FY1993 and remains the same for the rest of his time as chancellor. The files from that first year have been grouped with those of the same subject, but their title reflects this different mail log number.
The overall collection is divided into four series:
I. Mail Log Files
II. Subject Files
III. Chronological Files
IV. Speeches
Access Restrictions
Material in complaint files (1.10, 1.11, 1.12, 1.13, 5.12) has been restricted to protect the privacy of those writing to the Chancellor's Office. Researchers accessing these files will be required to sign a confidentiality agreement.
Scope and Content Note
The administrative files of J. Dennis O'Connor contain materials relating to all aspects of O'Connor's time as leader of the University of Pittsburgh, from 1991-1995. O'Connor began his time as "President" of the university, a holdover from the time of Wesley Posvar, but later asked the Board of Trustees to change the title back to "Chancellor." The records generally consist of correspondence, meeting minutes and supplementary materials, internal reports, university publications, chronological files, and speeches. It should be noted that many of the files in the O'Connor papers were facsimile printouts on heat transfer paper, which fades over time. As a result, all faxes have been photocopied and the originals removed from the collection.
The first series contains material sorted in the Office of the Chancellor's Mail Log File system, where every document has been previously categorized and sorted by the Chancellor's staff. Material within each mail log designation is sorted by fiscal year, which for the university begins on July 1st and ends June 30th of the next year (i.e., Fiscal Year 1992 is July 1, 1991 - June 30, 1992). Since Chancellor O'Connor stepped down on August 1, 1995, there is some material from FY1996 in the collection despite his only having been in office for one month of the fiscal year.
Chancellor O'Connor's collection continues after the mail log files with his chronological files, consisting of outgoing correspondence which may duplicate material present in the first series; his speeches, given at both Pitt and non-Pitt events; and subject files for materials not included in the mail log.
Areas of specific interest in the records may include the continuing development of Pitt's relationship with the University of Pittsburgh Medical Center (UPMC), increased development of affirmative action programs by the chancellor, and the creation of the university's Master Plan.
Acquisition Information
Transferred from the Office of the Chancellor in 2001.
University of Pittsburgh; Universities and colleges -- Research institutes; Universities and colleges -- Accreditation; Universities and colleges -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh -- Administration; Universities and colleges -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh -- Records and correspondence; Universities and colleges -- Pennsylvania; UPMC Health System; University of Pittsburgh. Chancellor; O'Connor, J. Dennis
- Mail Log Files, 1991-1995; I.
  Scope and Content Note
  The material in Series I comes from the mail log files and represents the bulk of the collection. The mail log files represent a filing structure put in place by the Chancellor's Office, creating categorizations for the records of that office. Their original order and assignments of mail log locations are retained here. The files of the mail log include correspondence, meeting materials, reports, and other publications. In a few exceptional cases there may be photographs included with the materials.
  The mail log files are arranged in order of ascending log number, and then within those categories chronologically by fiscal year. Chancellor O'Connor's materials include some in FY1996 because he did not step down officially until after the new fiscal year started.
  - Office of the Chancellor, 1.
    The 1.0 Mail Log file contains those records that directly relate to the Office of the Chancellor. These include materials specific to Chancellor O'Connor, such as correspondence not directly related to the operations of the university, memberships to boards of directors and trustees on which he served, activities overseen directly by the Office of the Chancellor, and records of Senior and Executive Staff meetings. The material in mail logs 1.10, 1.11, 1.12, and 1.25 are restricted and require a signed confidentiality agreement.
    - Office of the Chancellor, 1991-1995; 1.0.
      - 201.00. Office of the Chancellor, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
      - 1.0. Office of the Chancellor, 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - 1.0. Office of the Chancellor, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - 1.0. Office of the Chancellor, 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Letters, 1.1.
      - 201.13. Letters, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - 1.1. Letters, 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - 1.1. Letters, 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Boards of Directors and Memberships, 1.5.
      - 1.5. Boards of Directors and Memberships, 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Institute of Medicine, 1.5.1.
      - 1.5.1. Institute of Medicine, 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Pittsburgh National Bank (PNC), 1.5.2.
      - 1.5.2. Pittsburgh National Bank (PNC), 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - 1.5.2. Pittsburgh National Bank (PNC), 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - The Pittsburgh Symphony Society, 1.5.3.
      - 1.5.3. The Pittsburgh Symphony Society, 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - 1.5.3. The Pittsburgh Symphony Society, 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Urban League of Pittsburgh, 1.5.6.
      - 1.5.6. Urban League of Pittsburgh, 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - 1.5.6. Urban League of Pittsburgh, 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Pennsylvania Partnership for Children, 1.5.7.
      - 1.5.7. Pennsylvania Partnership for Children, 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Chancellor's Medallion, 1.7.
      - 1.7. Chancellor's Medallion, 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Senior Staff Meetings, 1.8.
      - 200.05B. Senior Staff Meetings, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 19)
      - 1.8. Senior Staff Meetings, 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 20)
      - 1.8. Senior Staff Meetings, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 21)
      - 1.8. Senior Staff Meetings, 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 22-23)
    - Executive Staff Meetings, 1.9.
      - 200.05A. Executive Staff Meetings, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 24)
      - 1.9. Executive Staff Meetings, 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 25-26)
      - 1.9. Executive Staff Meetings, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 27)
      - 1.9. Executive Staff Meetings, 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 28-29)
    - Complaints - Faculty [RESTRICTED], 1.10.
      - 200.07A. Complaints - Faculty [RESTRICTED], 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 30)
      - 1.10. Complaints - Faculty [RESTRICTED], 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 31)
      - 1.10. Complaints - Faculty [RESTRICTED], 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - 1.10. Complaints - Faculty [RESTRICTED], 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - 1.10. Complaints - Faculty [RESTRICTED], 1995-1996 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Complaints - Staff [RESTRICTED], 1.11.
      - 1.11. Complaints - Staff [RESTRICTED], 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - 1.11. Complaints - Staff [RESTRICTED], 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - 1.11. Complaints - Staff [RESTRICTED], 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Complaints - Student [RESTRICTED], 1.12.
      - 200.07C. Student Complaints, 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 7)
      - 1.12. Complaints - Student [RESTRICTED], 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - 1.12. Complaints - Student [RESTRICTED], 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Complaints and Grievances - Miscellaneous [RESTRICTED], 1.13.
      - 200.07. Complaints and Grievances [RESTRICTED], 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 10)
      - 1.13. Complaints and Grievances - Miscellaneous {RESTRICTED], 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 11-12)
      - 1.13. Complaints and Grievances - Miscellaneous, 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 13-14)
      - 1.13. Complaints and Grievances - Miscellaneous, 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Condolence - In Memoriam, 1.14.
      - 201.13A. Condolence - In Memoriam, 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 16)
      - 1.14. Condolence - In Memoriam, 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 17)
      - 1.14. Condolence - In Memoriam, 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 18)
      - 1.14. Condolence - In Memoriam, 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Congratulations, 1.15.
      - 201.13D. Congratulations, 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 20)
      - 1.15. Congratulations, 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 21)
      - 1.15. Congratulations, 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 22)
      - 1.15. Congratulations, 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 23)
      - 1.15. Congratulations, 1995-1996 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Thank You, 1.16.
      - 201.13C. Thank You, 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 25)
      - 1.16. Thank You, 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 26)
      - 1.16. Thank You, 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 27)
      - 1.16. Thank You, 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 28)
      - 1.16. Thank You, 1995-1996 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Invitations Received, 1.17.
      - 201.12A. Invitations Received, 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 30)
      - 1.17. Invitations Received, 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 31)
      - 1.17. Invitations Received, 1993-1994 (Box 3, Folder 1-7)
      - 1.17. Invitations Received, 1994-1995 (Box 3, Folder 8-12)
      - 1.17. Invitations Received, 1994-1995 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - 1.17. Invitations Received, 1995-1996 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Invitations to Conferences and Symposiums, 1.18.
      - 1.18. Invitations to Conferences and Symposiums, 1993-1994 (Box 4, Folder 3-4)
      - 1.18. Invitations to Conferences and Symposiums, 1994-1995 (Box 4, Folder 5-10)
      - 1.18. Invitations to Conferences and Symposiums, 1995-1996 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Solicitations, 1.19.
      - 200.09. Solicitations, 1991-1992 (Box 4, Folder 12)
      - 1.19. Solicitations, 1993-1994 (Box 4, Folder 13-15)
      - 1.19. Solicitations, 1994-1995 (Box 4, Folder 16)
      - 1.19. Solicitations, 1994-1995 (Box 5, Folder 1-3)
      - 1.19. Solicitations, 1995-1996 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Surveys and Questionnaires, 1.20.
      - 201.14. Surveys and Questionnaires, 1991-1992 (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - 1.20. Surveys and Questionnaires, 1993-1994 (Box 5, Folder 6)
      - 1.20. Surveys and Questionnaires, 1994-1995 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Recommendations, Commendations, References, 1.21.
      - 201.13E. Recommendations, Commendations, References, 1991-1992 (Box 5, Folder 8)
      - 1.21. Recommendations, Commendations, References, 1992-1993 (Box 5, Folder 9)
      - 1.21. Recommendations, Commendations, References, 1993-1994 (Box 5, Folder 10)
      - 1.21. Recommendations, Commendations, References, 1994-1995 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Recruiting Requests, 1.23.
      - 1.23. Recruiting Requests, 1992-1993 (Box 5, Folder 12)
      - 1.23. Recruiting Requests, 1993-1994 (Box 5, Folder 13)
      - 1.23. Recruiting Requests, 1994-1995 (Box 5, Folder 14)
      - 1.23. Recruiting Requests, 1995-1996 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - General Clippings, 1.24.
      - 201.26. General Clippings, 1991-1992 (Box 5, Folder 16)
      - 1.24. General Clippings, 1992-1993 (Box 5, Folder 17)
      - 1.24. General Clippings, 1993-1994 (Box 5, Folder 18-19)
      - 1.24. General Clippings, 1994-1995 (Box 5, Folder 20)
      - 1.24. General Clippings, 1995-1996 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Crank Letters, 1.25.
      - 1.25. Crank Letters, 1993-1994 (Box 5, Folder 22)
      - 1.25. Crank Letters, 1994-1995 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Public Affairs, 1.26.
      - 1.26. Public Affairs, 1993-1994 (Box 5, Folder 24)
      - 1.26. Public Affairs, 1994-1995 (Box 5, Folder 25-26)
      - 1.26. Public Affairs, 1994-1995 (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
    - Dr. Nancy Washington - Diversity Task Force, 1.27.
      - 1.27. Dr. Nancy Washington - Diversity Task Force, 1993-1994 (Box 6, Folder 3-9)
      - 1.27. Dr. Nancy Washington - Diversity Task Force, 1994-1995 (Box 6, Folder 10-13)
      - 1.27. Dr. Nancy Washington - Diversity Task Force, 1994-1995 (Box 7, Folder 1-2)
    - Technology Transfer Committee, 1.28.
      - 1.28. Technology Transfer Committee, 1992-1993 (Box 7, Folder 3)
      - 1.28. Technology Transfer Committee, 1993-1994 (Box 7, Folder 4-5)
      - 1.28. Technology Transfer Committee, 1994-1995 (Box 7, Folder 6-7)
    - University Space Allocation Committee, 1.29.
      - 1.29. University Space Allocation Committee, 1994-1995 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Rooney Fellowships, 1.30.
      - 1.30. Rooney Fellowships, 1995-1996 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Secretary of the University, 2.
    Materials in the 2.0 Mail Log files are directly concerned with the Board of Trustees of the University of Pittsburgh, and the committees created from its members. These include individual committee correspondence and meeting files, as well as correspondence with the Chancellor concerning various representatives to the Board and its committees.
    - Secretary of the University, 2.0.
      - 100.00. Board of Trustees, 1991-1992 (Box 7, Folder 10)
      - 2.0. Secretary of the University, 1992-1993 (Box 7, Folder 11)
      - 2.0. Secretary of the University, 1993-1994 (Box 7, Folder 12-16)
      - 2.0. Secretary of the University, 1994-1995 (Box 7, Folder 17)
      - 2.0. Secretary of the University, 1994-1995 (Box 8, Folder 1-5)
      - 2.0. Secretary of the University, 1995-1996 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Chancellor Search, 2.00.
      - 2.00. Chancellor Search, 1994-1995 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - By-Laws, 2.1.
      - 2.1. By-Laws, 1992-1993 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Members and Nominations for Membership, 2.2.
      - 102.00. Members and Nominations for Membership, 1991-1992 (Box 8, Folder 9)
      - 2.2. Members and Nominations for Membership, 1992-1993 (Box 8, Folder 10)
      - 2.2. Members and Nominations for Membership, 1993-1994 (Box 8, Folder 11)
      - 2.2. Members and Nominations for Membership, 1994-1995 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Agenda for Meetings and Meeting Minutes, 2.3.
      - 2.3. Agenda for Meetings and Meeting Minutes, 1992-1993 (Box 8, Folder 13-14)
      - 2.3. Agenda for Meetings and Meeting Minutes, 1993-1994 (Box 8, Folder 15-18)
      - 2.3. Agenda for Meetings and Meeting Minutes, 1994-1995 (Box 8, Folder 19)
      - 2.3. Agenda for Meetings and Meeting Minutes, 1994-1995 (Box 9, Folder 1-3)
    - Approvals and Resolutions, 2.4.
      - 2.4. Approvals and Resolutions, 1993-1994 (Box 9, Folder 4)
      - 2.4. Approvals and Resolutions, 1994-1995 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Commonwealth Trustees, 2.5.
      - 106.00. Commonwealth Trustees, 1991-1992 (Box 9, Folder 6)
      - 2.5. Commonwealth Trustees, 1992-1993 (Box 9, Folder 7)
      - 2.5. Commonwealth Trustees, 1993-1994 (Box 9, Folder 8)
      - 2.5. Commonwealth Trustees, 1994-1995 (Box 9, Folder 9)
      - 2.5. Commonwealth Trustees, 1995-1996 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Trustee Emeritus, 2.6.
      - 2.6. Trustee Emeritus, 1992-1993 (Box 9, Folder 11)
      - 2.6. Trustee Emeritus, 1993-1994 (Box 9, Folder 12)
      - 2.6. Trustee Emeritus, 1994-1995 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Trustee Medallion and Certificates, 2.7.
      - 2.7. Trustee Medallion and Certificates, 1994-1995 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Trustee Committees, 107.00
      - 107.00. Trustee Committees, 1994-1995 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Academic Affairs and Libraries Committee, 2.8.
      - 2.8. Academic Affairs and Libraries Committee, 1992-1993 (Box 9, Folder 16)
      - 2.8. Academic Affairs and Libraries Committee, 1993-1994 (Box 9, Folder 17)
      - 2.8. Academic Affairs and Libraries Committee, 1994-1995 (Box 9, Folder 18-19)
    - Affirmative Action Committee, 2.9.
      - 2.9. Affirmative Action Committee, 1992-1993 (Box 9, Folder 20)
      - 2.9. Affirmative Action Committee, 1993-1994 (Box 9, Folder 21)
      - 2.9. Affirmative Action Committee, 1994-1995 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Audit Committee, 2.10.
      - 107.01. Budget-Audit Committee, 1991-1992 (Box 9, Folder 23)
      - 2.10. Audit Committee, 1992-1993 (Box 9, Folder 24)
      - 2.10. Audit Committee, 1993-1994 (Box 9, Folder 25-26)
      - 2.10. Audit Committee, 1994-1995 (Box 9, Folder 27-28)
    - Budget Committee, 2.11.
      - 2.11. Budget Committee, 1992-1993 (Box 9, Folder 29)
      - 2.11. Budget Committee, 1993-1994 (Box 10, Folder 1-4)
      - 2.11. Budget Committee, 1994-1995 (Box 10, Folder 5-7)
    - Compensation Committee, 2.12.
      - 107.12. Compensation Committee, 1991-1992 (Box 10, Folder 8)
      - 2.12. Compensation Committee, 1992-1993 (Box 10, Folder 9)
      - 2.12. Compensation Committee, 1993-1994 (Box 10, Folder 10)
      - 2.12. Compensation Committee, 1994-1995 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Executive Committee, 2.13.
      - 2.13. Executive Committee, 1992-1993 (Box 10, Folder 12)
      - 2.13. Executive Committee, 1993-1994 (Box 10, Folder 13)
      - 2.13. Executive Committee, 1994-1995 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Health Sciences Committee, 2.14.
      - 2.14. Health Sciences Committee, 1993-1994 (Box 10, Folder 15)
      - 2.14. Health Sciences Committee, 1994-1995 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Institutional Development Committee, 2.15.
      - 2.15. Institutional Development Committee, 1993-1994 (Box 10, Folder 17)
      - 2.15. Institutional Development Committee, 1994-1995 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Investment Committee, 2.16.
      - 2.16. Investment Committee, 1992-1993 (Box 10, Folder 19)
      - 2.16. Investment Committee, 1993-1994 (Box 10, Folder 20-21)
      - 2.16. Investment Committee, 1994-1995 (Box 11, Folder 1-2)
    - Nominating Committee, 2.17.
      - 02.17. Nominating Committee, 1992-1993 (Box 11, Folder 3)
      - 02.17. Nominating Committee, 1993-1994 (Box 11, Folder 4)
      - 02.17. Nominating Committee, 1994-1995 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Property and Facilities Committee, 2.18.
      - 2.18. Property and Facilities Committee, 1992-1993 (Box 11, Folder 7)
      - 2.18. Property and Facilities Committee, 1993-1994 (Box 11, Folder 8-10)
      - 2.18. Property and Facilities Committee, 1994-1995 (Box 11, Folder 11-12)
    - Student Affairs Committee, 2.19.
      - 2.19. Student Affairs Committee, 1993-1994 (Box 11, Folder 13)
      - 2.19. Student Affairs Committee, 1994-1995 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Property and Facilities Committee, 2.20.
      - 2.20. Property and Facilities Committee, 1992-1993 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - University Trust, 2.21.
      - 2.21. University Trust, 1992-1993 (Box 11, Folder 16)
      - 2.21. University Trust, 1993-1994 (Box 11, Folder 17-19)
      - 2.21. University Trust, 1994-1995 (Box 11, Folder 20-21)
      - 2.21. University Trust, 1995-1996 (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - National Defense Environmental Corporation, 109.00A
      - 109.00A. National Defense Environmental Corporation, 1991-1992 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - University of Pittsburgh Applied Research Center (U-PARC), 2.21.1.
      - 501.00. University of Pittsburgh Applied Research Center (U-PARC), 1991-1992 (Box 12, Folder 2)
      - 2.21.1. University of Pittsburgh Applied Research Center (U-PARC), 1992-1993 (Box 12, Folder 3)
      - 2.21.1. University of Pittsburgh Applied Research Center (U-PARC), 1993-1994 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Bituminous Coal Research, 2.21.2.
      - 502.00. Bituminous Coal Research, 1991-1992 (Box 12, Folder 5)
      - 2.21.2. Bituminous Coal Research, 1992-1993 (Box 12, Folder 6)
      - 2.21.2. Bituminous Coal Research, 1993-1994 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Center for Biotechnology and Bioengineering, 2.21.3.
      - 506.01. Center for Biotechnology and Bioengineering, 1991-1992 (Box 12, Folder 8)
      - 2.21.3. Center for Biotechnology and Bioengineering, 1992-1993 (Box 12, Folder 9)
      - 2.21.3. Center for Biotechnology and Bioengineering, 1993-1994 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Center for Hazardous Materials Research (CHMR), 2.21.4.
      - 2.21.4. Center for Hazardous Materials Research (CHMR), 1992-1993 (Box 12, Folder 11)
      - 2.21.4. Center for Hazardous Materials Research (CHMR), 1993-1994 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Metalworking Technology Inc. (MTI) - Concurrent Technologies Corporation, 2.21.6.
      - 2.21.6. Metalworking Technology Inc. (MTI) - Concurrent Technologies Corporation, 1992-1993 (Box 12, Folder 13-14)